<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_90"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_90_z018">90</metamark></ab><ab><lb/><lb/>XIII<lb/>The <subst facs="#rboc-d_90_z001"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_90_z001">sl</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_90_z001">co</add></subst>lumn that had butted stoutly at the obstacles in the
  <lb/>roadway was barely out of Fleming's sight before he saw
  <lb/>dark waves of men come sweeping out of the woods and
  <lb/>down through the fields. He knew at once that the steel
  <lb/>fibres had been washed from their hearts. They were burst
  <lb/>ing from their coats and their equipments as from en
  <lb/>tangling things. They charged down upo<restore change="dstX" hand="#SC" facs="#rboc-d_90_z015">n</restore> him like ter
  <lb/>rified buffalos.
  <lb/>Behind them, blue smoke curled and clouded,
  <lb/>and, through the thickets, he could sometimes <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_90_z003">see</add><metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_90_z017">^</metamark> a dis
  <lb/>tant, pink glare. The <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_90_z004">cannon's'</del> voices of the cannon
  <lb/>were clamoring in an interminable chorus.
  <lb/>Fleming was horror-stricken. He stared in pain
  <lb/>and amazement. He forgot that nature had pointed
  <lb/>him out as a victim. He again lost all concern for
  <lb/>himself. He threw aside his mental pamphlets on the
  <lb/>philosophy of the retreated and rules for the guid
  <lb/>ance of the doomed.
  <lb/>The fight was lost. The foe was coming
  <lb/>storm-wise to flood the army.
  <lb/>Within him there was something that bade him
  <lb/>cry out. He had the impulse to make a rallying <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_90_z005">or</del>
  <lb/>speech, to sing a battle-hymn, but he could only
  <lb/>get his tongue to call out into the air: "Why--why--
  <lb/>what--what's th' matter?"
  <lb/>Soon he was in the midst of them. They were
  <lb/>leaping and scampering all about him. Their blanched
  <lb/>faces shone in the dusk.
</ab><milestone n="13" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>