<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_10"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_10_z008">10</metamark></ab><ab><lb/>The only foes he had seen were the pickets on the
  <lb/>river bank. They were a sun-tanned, philosophical
  <lb/>lot who sometimes shot thoughtfully at the oppos-
  <lb/>ite pickets but usually seemed sorry for it af-
  <lb/>terwards. Fleming on guard duty one night had
  <lb/>talked across the river w:ith one. He was a
  <lb/>slightly ragged man with a fund of sublime
  <lb/>assurance. Fleming liked him personally.
  <lb/>Various veterans had told him tales. Some
  <lb/>talked of grey, be-whiskered hordes who were
  <lb/>advancing, <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_10_z006">chewing tobacco</del> cursing relentlessly
  <lb/>and chewing tobacco with unspeakable valor;
  <lb/>tremendous bodies of fierce soldiery who were
  <lb/>sweeping along like the Huns. Others spoke
  <lb/>of tattered and eternally hungry men who fired
  <lb/>despondent rifles. From their stories, <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_10_z004">one</del> <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_10_z003">could</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_10_z005">Fleming</add>
  <lb/>imagine<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_10_z014">d</add> the red bones sticking out through <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_10_z002">the</del>
  <lb/>slits in the faded uniforms. Still, he could not
  <lb/>put <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_10_z001">faith</del> a whole faith in tales, for re-
  <lb/>cruits were the veteran's prey. They talked much
  <lb/>of smoke, fire and blood but he could not
  <lb/>tell how much might be lies.
  <lb/>However, he percieved that it did not greatly
  <lb/>matter what kind of soldiers he was going to
  <lb/>fight. There was a more serious problem. He
  <lb/>lay in his bunk debating the question. He
  <lb/>tried to solve it mathematically. He was en-
  <lb/>deavoring to decide wether he would run
  <lb/>from a fight or not.
  <lb/>It had suddenly come to his mind that
  <lb/>perhaps in a battle he might run. He was
</ab><milestone n="1" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>