<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_49"/><ab><lb/>49<lb/>A man near him who up to this time had been work
  <lb/>ing <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z004">feverishly</add> <metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z021">^</metamark>at his rifle, suddenly dropped it <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z005">r</del> and ran with
  <lb/>howls. A lad whose face had born an expression of exalted cour
  <lb/>age, the majesty of he who dares give his life, was smitten ab
  <lb/>ject. He blanched like one who has come to the edge of a cliff
  <lb/>at midnight and is suddenly made aware. There was a revel
  <lb/>ation. He too threw down his gun and <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z007">ran</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z020">fled</add>. There was no
  <lb/>shame in his face. He ran like a rabbit.
  <lb/>Others began to scamper away through the smoke.
  <lb/>Fleming turned his head, shaken from his trance by this
  <lb/>movement as if the regiment was leaving him behind. He
  <lb/>saw the few fleeting forms.
  <lb/>He yelled then with fright and swung about. For
  <lb/>a moment, in the clamor, he was like a proverbial
  <lb/>chicken. He lost the direction of safety. Destruction
  <lb/>threatened him from all points.
  <lb/>Directly he began to speed toward the rear
  <lb/>in great leaps. His rifle and cap were gone. <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z010">His un</del>
  <lb/><del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z011">buttoned coat streamed out</del>.The flap of his cart
  <lb/>ridge-box <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z013">and his</del> bobbed wildly. His canteen
  <lb/>swung <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z014">on a cord</del> out behind him. On his face
  <lb/>was a <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z015">on</del> reflected horror of those things which
  <lb/>he imagined.
  <lb/>He ran like a blind man. Two or three
  <lb/>times, he fell down and once he knocked his
  <lb/>shoulder so heavily against a tree that he went head-
  <lb/>long. He felt that death was ever about to thrust
  <lb/>him between the shoulder blades.
  <lb/>He ran on mingling with others. He <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_49_z018">saw men</del> 
  <lb/>vaguely saw men on his right and on his left, and he
  <lb/>heard foot-steps behind him. He thought that all
  <lb/>the regiment was running. Ominous noises were following.
</ab><milestone n="6" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>