<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_48"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="above" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_48_z001">48</metamark></ab><ab rend="bottom"><metamark place="below" function="caret" rend="ink" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_48_z002">^</metamark></ab><ab><lb/><lb/>in the great clouds <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_48_z003">that were</add> tinged with an earthlike yel-
  <lb/>low in the sun-rays, and changed to a sor-
  <lb/>ry blue in the shadows.
  <lb/>Fleming's eyes had a look in them that one can 
  <lb/>see in the orbs of a jaded horse. The muscles of his 
  <lb/>arms <subst facs="#rboc-d_48_z005"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_48_z005">left</del><add place="above" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_48_z005">felt</add></subst> numb and bloodless. His hands, too, seemed 
  <lb/>large and awkward as if he were wearing invisible 
  <lb/>mittens. And there was a great uncertainty about his knee-joints.
  <lb/>The words that comrades had uttered previous to 
  <lb/>the firing began to appear to him. "Oh, say, this is too 
  <lb/>much of a good thing." "What do they take us fer--why 
  <lb/>don't they send us supports." "I didn't come here t' fight 
  <lb/>th' hull damn rebel army."
  <lb/>He began to exaggerate the endurance, the skill 
  <lb/>and the valor of those who were coming. They must be
  <lb/>steel machines. Himself, reeling from nervous exhaustion, 
  <lb/>he could not understand such persistency.
  <lb/>He mechanically lifted his rifle and, catching 
  <lb/>a glimpse of <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_48_z009">a cantering cluster</del> the thick-spread field,
  <lb/>he fired a shot at a cantering<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_48_z008">ly</del> cluster. He stopped 
  <lb/>then and began to gaze as best he could through the 
  <lb/>smoke. He caught changing views of the ground 
  <lb/>covered with men who were all running and yell-
  <lb/>ing like pursued imps.
  <lb/>To him, it was an onslaught of dragons. He be
  <lb/>came like the m<subst facs="#rboc-d_48_z006"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_48_z006">e</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_48_z006">a</add></subst>n who lost his legs at the ap-
  <lb/>proach of the red and green monster. He waited
  <lb/>in a sort of a horrified, listening attitude. He 
  <lb/>seemed to shut his eyes and wait to be gobbled.
</ab><milestone n="6" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>