<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_60"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_60_z018">60</metamark></ab><ab><lb/>It occurred to him that the fight he had been in, was,
  <lb/>after all, but perfunctory <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z001">popping</add><metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z019">^</metamark>. In the hearing of this present
  <lb/>din, he was doubtful if he had seen real <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z002">war</del>battle-
  <lb/>scenes. Reflecting, he saw a sort <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z003">of a</del>humor in the point
  <lb/>of view of he and his fellows during that encounter. They
  <lb/>had taken themselves and the enemy very seriously and
  <lb/>had imagined that they were deciding the war. Individuals
  <lb/>might have supposed that they were cutting the letters
  <lb/>of their names deep into everlasting tablets of brass
  <lb/>or enshrining their reputations forever in the hearts of
  <lb/>their countrymen, while, as to fact, the affair would
  <lb/>appear in reports under a <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z004">curious</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z005">meek</add> and <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z006">meek</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z014">immaterial</add> title.
  <lb/>But he saw that it was good, else, he said, in battle ev-
  <lb/>eryone would doubtless run save for lorn hope and their ilk.
  <lb/>He went rapidly <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z007">on</del>on. He wanted <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z008">to</add> come to the
  <lb/>edge of the forest and peer out.
  <lb/>As he hurried, there passed through his mind
  <lb/>pictures of stupendous struggles. All his accumulations
  <lb/>upon such subjects were used to form scenes. The up-
  <lb/>roar was as <subst facs="#rboc-d_60_z017"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z017">a</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z017">t</add></subst>he voice of an eloquent being describing.
  <lb/>Sometimes, the brambles formed chains and held
  <lb/>him back. Trees, confronting him stretched out their
  <lb/>arms and forbade him to pass. <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z009">It seemed to him</del>
  <lb/><del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z010">that</del>He thought with a fine bitterness that nature
  <lb/>could not be quite ready to kill him yet.
  <lb/>But he took roundabout ways. Presently he was
  <lb/>in a place from which he could see long fringes
  <lb/>of smoke where battle-lines lay. The voices of
  <lb/>the cannon shook him. He stood for a moment
  <lb/>and watched. His <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_60_z011">I</del>eyes had an awe-struck ex-
  <lb/>pression. His lower jaw hung down.
</ab><milestone n="8" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>