<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_77"/><ab><lb/>77<lb/>XI<lb/>He became aware that the furnace-roar of the battle was 
  <lb/>growing louder. Great brown clouds had floated to the still 
  <lb/>heights of air before him. The noise, too, was approaching. 
  <lb/>The woods filtered men and the fields became dotted.
  <lb/>As he rounded a hillock, he percieved that the road-
  <lb/>way was now a crying mass of wagons, teams and men. From 
  <lb/>the heaving tangle issued exhortations, cammands and im-
  <lb/>precations. Fear was sweeping it all along. The biting
  <lb/>cracking whips bit, and horses plunged and tugged. The 
  <lb/>white-topped wagons strained and stumbled in their exertions 
  <lb/>like fat sheep.
  <lb/>Fleming felt in a measure comforted by the sight. 
  <lb/>They were all retreating. Perhaps, then, he was not so bad 
  <lb/>after all. He seated himself and watched the fleeing wag-
  <lb/>ons. All the roarers and lashers served to help him to 
  <lb/>magnify the dangers and horrors of anthe engagement 
  <lb/>that he might try to prove to himself that the thing 
  <lb/>with which men mightcould charge him, was, in truth, 
  <lb/>a symetrical act.
  <lb/>Presently, the calm head of a column of infantry ap-
  <lb/>peared in the road. It came swiftly on. Avoiding 
  <lb/>the obstructions gave it the sinuous movement of a 
  <lb/>long serpent. The men at the head butted mules with 
  <lb/>their musket-stocks. They prodded teamsters, indifferent 
  <lb/>to all howls. The men forced their way through parts 
  <lb/>of the dense mass by strength. The blunt head of the 
  <lb/>column pushed. The wild teamsters swore many strange 
  <lb/>oaths.
  <lb/>The cammands to make way had the ring of a 
  <lb/>great importance in them. The men were going for-
  <lb/>ward. They were to confront the eager rush of the
</ab><ab><add place="margin-top" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z003">78</add><milestone n="11" unit="chapter"/></ab></div></body></text>