<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_81"/><ab><lb/><metamark place="inline" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_81_z018">81</metamark><lb/>time might mean many things to him. The blows of 
  <lb/>the enemy would splinter regiments into fragments. 
  <lb/>Many men of courage, he thought, would be compelled to 
  <lb/>desert the colors and scurry like chickens. He would ap-
  <lb/>pear as one of them. They would all be sullen brothers 
  <lb/>in distress and he could then easily believe that he had 
  <lb/>not run any further or faster than others.
  <lb/>He said, as if in excuse, that, previously, the army 
  <lb/>had <subst facs="#rboc-d_81_z004"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z004">sh</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dStX" facs="#rboc-d_81_z004"/></subst>encountered great defeats and in a few months had 
  <lb/>shaken off all blood and tradition of <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z014">it</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z013">them</add> emerging as bright 
  <lb/>and valiant as a new one<del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z016">.</del><add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z017">;</add> thrusting out of sight the 
  <lb/>very traditions of disaster and appearing with <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z008">the</add> valor 
  <lb/>and confidence of unconquered legions. The shrilling 
  <lb/>voices of the people at home <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z015">would</add> pipe<del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z009">d</del> dismally for a 
  <lb/>time but various generals <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z010">were</del>would be compelled 
  <lb/>to listen <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z011">to</del>to the ditties.
  <lb/>In a defeat there would be a roundabout 
  <lb/>moral vindication of himself. He thought that it 
  <lb/>would prove, in a way, that he had fled early be-
  <lb/>cause of his superior powers of perception. This he re-
  <lb/>garded as a very important thing. Without salve, 
  <lb/>he could not, he said, wear the sore badge of his 
  <lb/>dishonor through life. With his heart continually as-
  <lb/>suring him that he was despicable, he could not 
  <lb/>exist without making it apparent to all men, im-
  <lb/>parting the information through his actions.
  <lb/>But if the army had gone gloriously on, he 
  <lb/>would be indeed lost. If the din meant that now 
  <lb/>his army's flags were tilted forward he was a 
  <lb/>condemned wretch. He would be compelled be doom him-
  <lb/>self to isolation. If the men were advancing, their indif-
  <lb/>ferent feet were trampling upon his chances <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dStB" facs="#rboc-d_81_z012">of</del> for a successful 
  <lb/>life.
</ab><milestone n="11" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>