<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_093"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_093_z001">93</metamark></ab><ab>
<add place="margin-top" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z001">
</add>	
<lb/>	Eventually, his courage expended itself upon the<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z020">se</add> objections. The debates drained him of his fire.
  <lb/>	He was not cast-down by this defeat of his plan, for, upon studying <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z005">the</add><metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z026">^</metamark> affair carefully, he could not but admit that the objections were very formidable.  
  <lb/>	<del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z006">Further, various ailments</del><add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093-0007">Furthermore, various ailments</add> had begun to cry out. In their presence, he could not persist in flying high with the red wings of war; they rendered it almost impossible for him to see himself in a heroic light. He tumbled headlong.
  <lb/>	He discovered that he had a scorching th<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z008">r</del>irst. His face was so dry and grimey that he thought he could feel his skin crackle. Each bone of his body had an ache in it and seemingly 
<subst facs="#ms_093_z009"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z009">r</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z009">th</add></subst>reatened to break<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z010">.</del> with each movement. His feet were like two sores. Also, his body was calling for food. It was more powerful than a direct hunger. There was a dull, weight-like feeling in his stomach and 
  <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z011">his head</del>when he tried to walk, his head swayed and he tottered. He could not see with distinctness. Small patches of crimson mist floated before his vision.
  <lb/>	While he had been tossed by many emotions, he had not been aware of ailments. Now they beset him and made clamor. <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mstX" facs="#ms_093_z013">The</del> <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mstX" facs="#ms_093_z012">dogs of pain</del>As he was at last compelled to pay attention to them, his capacity for self-hate was multiplied. In despair, he declared that he was not like those others. He now conceded it to be impossible that he should ever become a hero. He was a craven 
  <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z015">look</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z014">loon</add>. Those pictures of glory were piteous things. He groaned from his heart and went staggering off.
  <lb/>	A certain moth-like quality within him kept 
  <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z019">him</add><metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z028">^</metamark> in the vicinity of the battle. He had a great desire to see, and <add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_093_z023">to</add> get news. He wished to know who was winning.
</ab><milestone n="11" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>