<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_040"/><ab>  <lb/>"That young Hasbrouck<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z004">.</del>, he makes a good off'cer. <subst facs="#ms_040_z005"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z005">h</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z005">H<subst facs="#ms_040_z006"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z006"/><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z006"/></subst>M</add></subst>e aint 
  <lb/>afraid 'a nothin'."
  <lb/>"I met one of th' 148th Maine boys an' he ses his brigade fit 
  <lb/>th' hull rebel army fer four hours over on th' turnpike-road an' killed about 
  <lb/>five thousand of'em. He ses one more sech fight as that an' th' war'll be over."
  <lb/>"Bill wasn't scared either. No, sir. It wasn't that. Bill aint a-gittin'
  <lb/>scared easy. He was jest mad, that's what he was. When 
  <lb/>that feller trod on his hand, he up an' sed that he was willin' t' give
  <lb/>his hand t' his country but he b<add place="inline" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z007">b</add>e dumbed if he was gain' t' have every 
  <lb/>dumb bushwhacker in th' kentry walkin' 'round on it. So he went 
  <lb/>t' th' hospital disregardless of th' fight. Three fingers was crunched. 
  <lb/>Th' dern doctor wanted t' amputate'm an' Bill, he raised a 
  <lb/>heluva row, I hear. He's a funny feller."
  <lb/>"Hear that what th' ol' colonel se<add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z008">e</add>s, boys. He ses he'll 
  <lb/>shoot th' first man what'll tum an' run."
  <lb/>"He'd better try it. I'd like t' see him shoot at me."
  <lb/>"He wants t' look fer his ownself. He don't wanta go 
  <lb/>'round talkin' big."
  <lb/>"They say Perrey's division's a-givin'em thunder."
  <lb/>"Ed Williams over in Company A, he ses th' rebs'll all 
  <lb/>drop their guns an' run an' holler if we onct giv'e<subst facs="#ms_040_z009"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z009">e</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z009">i</add></subst>m one good lickin'."
  <lb/>"Oh, thunder, Ed Williams, what does he know?<restore change="mStB" hand="#SC" facs="#ms_040_z014">?</restore> Ever since he got 
  <lb/>shot at on picket, he's been runnin' th' war."
  <lb/>"Well<restore change="mStB" hand="#SC" facs="#ms_040_z013">,</restore>, he--"
  <lb/>"Hear th' news, boys?<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z010">?</del> Corkright's crushed th' hull rebel right 
  an' captured two hull divisions. We'll be back in winter quarters
  by a short cut t'morrah."
  <lb/>"I tell yeh I've been all over that there kentry where th' rebel 
  right is an it's th' nastiest part th' rebel line. It's all mussed up 
  with hills an' little damn creeks. I'll bet m'shirt Corkright 
  never harmed'em down there."
  <lb/>"Well<add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_040_z011">,</add> he's a fighter an' if they could be licked, he'd lick'em."
</ab><milestone n="5" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>