<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_058"/><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_058_z023">58</metamark><ab><lb/>battery's formation would appear a little thing when the
  <lb/>infantry came swooping out of the woods.
  <lb/>The face of a youthful rider who was jerking his fran-
  <lb/>tic horse with an abandon of temper he might display in a placid
  <lb/>barn-yard was impressed deep upon his mind. He knew that 
  <lb/>he looked upon a man who would presently be dead.
  <lb/>Too, <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z003">fe</del> he felt a pity for the guns, standing, six 
  <lb/>good comrades, in <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z004">their</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z005">a</add> bold row.
  <lb/>He saw a brigade going to the relief of it's pestered
  <lb/>fellows. He scrambled upon a wee hill and watched it
  <lb/>sweeping finely, keeping formation in difficult places. The 
  <lb/>blue of the line was crusted with steel-color and the
  <lb/>brilliant flags projected. Officer<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z009">'</del>s were shouting.
  <lb/>This sight, also, filled him with wonder. The brigade 
  <lb/>was hurrying briskly to be gulped into the infernal mouth of the war-
  <lb/>god. What <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z010">kind</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z011">manner</add> of men were they, anyhow. Ah, it was some wondrous<subst facs="#ms_058_z014"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z014">s</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z014"/></subst> 
  <lb/>breed. Or else they didnt comprehend--the fools.
  <lb/>A furious<metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStE" facs="#ms_058_z024">^</metamark> <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z015">order</add> caused commotion in the artillery. An officer
  <lb/>on a bounding horse made maniacal motions with his 
  <lb/>arms. The teams went swinging up from the rear, the
  <lb/>guns were whirled about, and the battery scampered away. 
  <lb/>The cannon with their noses poked slantingly at the ground 
  <lb/>grunted and grumbled like stout men, brave but with objections to hurry.
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_058_z016">Fleming</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_058_z017">The youth</add> went on, moderating his pace since he 
  <lb/>had left the place of noises .
  <lb/>Later, he came upon a general of division seated upon a horse that 
  <lb/>pricked it's ears in an interested way at the battle. There was <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z018">g</del> <add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z019">a</add> great 
  <lb/>gleaming of <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z021">silve</del> <add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_058_z022">yellow</add> and patent-leather about the saddle and bridle. 
  <lb/>The quiet man, astride, looked mouse-colored upon such a splendid charger.
  <lb/>A jingling staff was galloping hither and thither. Sometimes 
  <lb/>the general was surrounded by horsemen and at other times he was 
  <lb/>quite alone. He looked to be much harassed. He had the
</ab><milestone n="6" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>