<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_086-090"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_086-090_z002">90</metamark><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z020">XI</metamark></ab><ab rend="bottom"><metamark place="below" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z016">^</metamark></ab><ab><subst facs="#ms_086-090_z002"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z002"/><add place="inline" rend="bluepencil" hand="#SC" change="mstX" facs="#ms_086-090_z004">86--</add></subst><lb/>He became aware that the furnace-roar of the battle was grow-
  <lb/>ing louder. Great brown clouds had floated to the still heights
  <lb/>of air before him. The noise, too, was approaching. The woods
  <lb/>filtered men and the fields became dotted.
  <lb/>As he rounded a hillock, he percieved that the road-way was
  <lb/>now a crying mass of wagons, teams and men. From the heav-
  <lb/>ing tangle issued exhortations, cammands, imprecations. Fear
  <lb/>was sweeping it all along. The cracking whips bit and horses
  <lb/>plunged and tugged. The white-topped wagons strained and
  <lb/>stumbled in their exertions like fat sheep.
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z005">Fleming</del><add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_086-090_z006">The youth</add> <metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStE" facs="#ms_086-090_z017">^</metamark>felt comforted in a measure by this sight. They
  <lb/>were all <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z007">fleeing</del><add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z008">retreating</add>. Perhaps, then, he was not so bad
  <lb/>after all. He seated himself and watched the terror-stricken
  <lb/>wagons. They fled like soft, ungainly animals. All the
  <lb/>roarers and lashers served to help him to magnify the <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z009">hor</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z010">dangers</add>
  <lb/><add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z019">and horrors</add>of <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z015">an</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z011">the</add> engagement that he might try to prove to him-
  <lb/>self that the thing with which men <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z012">charge</del>could charge
  <lb/>him was in truth a symetrical act. There was an a-
  <lb/>mount of pleasure to him in watching the wild march of
  <lb/>this vindication.
  <lb/>Presently, the calm head of a <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_086-090_z013">forward-going </add> column of infantry appear-
  <lb/>ed in the road. It came swiftly on. Avoiding the obstructions
  <lb/>gave it the sinuous movement of a serpent. The men at the
  <lb/>head butted mules with their musket-stocks. They prodded
  <lb/>teamsters, indifferent to all howls. The men forced their way
  <lb/>through parts of the dense mass by strength. The blunt head of
  <lb/>the column pushed. The raving teamsters swore many strange oaths.
  <lb/>The cammands to make way had the ring of a great
  <lb/>importance in them. The men were going forward to the
</ab><milestone n="11" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>