<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_033"/> <ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_033_z014">33</metamark></ab><ab> <lb/>During this march, the ardor which <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStC" facs="#ms_033_z002">fleming</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStC" facs="#ms_033_z003">the youth</add> had acquired
  <lb/>when out of view of the field rapidly faded to nothing.
  <lb/>His curiosity was quite easily satisfied. If an intense scene
  <lb/>had caught him with it's wild swing as he came to the
  <lb/>top of the bank he might have gone roaring on. This ad-
  <lb/>vance upon nature was too calm. He had opportunity
  <lb/>to reflect. He had time in which to wonder about him-
  <lb/>self and to attempt to probe his sensations.
  <lb/>A<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_033_z016">bsurd</add> ideas took hold upon him. He <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_033_z004">that</del> thought
  <lb/>that he did not relish the landscape. It threatened him. A
  <lb/>coldness swept over his back and it is true that his
  <lb/>trousers felt to him that they were no fit for his legs at all.
  <lb/>A house, standing placidly in distant fields
  <lb/>had to him an ominous look. The shadows of the
  <lb/>woods were formidable. He was certain that in this
  <lb/>vista there lurked fierce-eyed hosts. The swift thought
  <lb/>came to him that the generals did not know what they
  <lb/>were about. It was all a trap. Suddenly those close
  <lb/>forests would bristle with rifle-barrels. Iron-like
  <lb/>brigades would appear in the rear. They were all go-
  <lb/>ing to be sacrificed. The <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_033_z005">camm</del> generals were stupids. The
  <lb/>enemy would presently <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStC" facs="#ms_033_z006">encompass and</del> swallow the whole
  <lb/>cammand. He glared about him, expecting to see the
  <lb/>stealthy approach of his death.
  <lb/>He thought that he must break from the
  <lb/>ranks and harangue his comrades. They must not all
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStD" facs="#ms_033_z017">to</del> be killed like pigs. And he was sure it would
  <lb/>com<subst facs="#ms_033_z010"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStD" facs="#ms_033_z010">ing</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStD" facs="#ms_033_z010">e</add></subst> to pass unless <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_033_z007">some one</del> they were informed
  <lb/>of these dangers. The<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_033_z008">se</del> generals were idiots to send them
  <lb/>marching into a regular <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_033_z009">trap</del> pen. There was but
  <lb/>one pair of eyes in the corps. He would step forth
  <lb/>and make a speech. Shrill and passionate words came to
  <lb/>his lips.
</ab><milestone n="3" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>