<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_065"/>
<ab>
  65
  <lb/>and <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_065_z003">touched</del> brought it against a tree. Leaning upon this, 
  <lb/>he retreated, step by step, with his face still toward the thing. 
  <lb/>He feared, that if he <gap reason="undeciphered"/>his back, <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_065_z004">the</del> the body might 
  <lb/>spring up and stealthily pursue him.
  <lb/>The branches, pushing against <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_065_z005">th</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_065_z006">him</add>, threatened to throw 
  <lb/>him over upon it. His unguided feet, too, caught aggravat-
  <lb/>ingly in brambles. And, with it all, he recieved a subtle 
  <lb/>suggestion to touch the corpse. As he thought of his hand 
  <lb/>upon it, he shuddered profoundly.
  <lb/>At last, he burst the bounds which had fastened 
  <lb/>him to the spot and fled, unheeding the underbrush. He was 
  <lb/>pursued by a sight of the black<del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStC" facs="#ms_065_z008">s</del> ants swarming <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_065_z007">greedily</add> upon the grey 
  <lb/>face and venturing horribly near to the eyes.
  <lb/>After a time, he paused and, breathless and panting, 
  <lb/>listened. He imagined some strange voice would come from 
  <lb/>the dead throat and sqawk after him <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_065_z029">in</add> horrible menaces.
  <lb/><del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_065_z009">The trees</del> The trees about the portal of the chapel 
  <lb/>moved sighingly in a soft wind. A sad silence was 
  <lb/>upon the little, guarding edifice.
 <del rend="multistrikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStF" facs="#ms_065_z023"> <lb/>Again <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_065_z024">Fleming</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_065_z025">the youth</add> was in despair. Nature no long-
  <lb/>er condoled with him. There was nothing, then, after 
  <lb/>all, in that demonstration she gave--the fright-
  <lb/>ened squirrel <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_065_z027">alf</del> fleeing aloft from the missile.
  <lb/>He thought as he remembered the small animal<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_065_z028">,</del> 
  <lb/>capturing the fish and the greedy ants feeding upon 
  <lb/>the flesh of the dead soldier, that there was given 
  <lb/>another law which far-over-topped it--all life 
  <lb/>existing upon death, eating ravenously, stuffing 
  <lb/>itself with the hopes of the dead.
  <lb/>And nature's processes were obliged to hurry</del>
  <lb/>
</ab><milestone n="8" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>