<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_031"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_031_z010">31</metamark></ab><ab><lb/>He siezed time to look about him calculatingly.
  <lb/>But he instantly saw that it would be im
  <lb/>possible for him to escape from the regiment. It enclosed him. 
  <lb/>And there were iron laws of tradition and law on four 
  <lb/>sides. He was in a <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_031_z009">sort</del>moving box.<del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_031_z003">si</del>
  <lb/>As he percieved this fact, <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_031_z002">that</del> it occurred to 
  <lb/>him that he had never wished to come to the war. 
  <lb/>He had not enlisted of his free will. He had been 
  <lb/>dragged by the merciless government. And now they 
  <lb/>were taking him out to be slaughtered!
  <lb/>The regiment slid down a bank and wal-
  <lb/>lowed across a little stream. The mournful current 
  <lb/>moved slowly on and from the water, shaded black, 
  <lb/><add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_031_z004">some</add> white bubble-eyes looked at the men.
  <lb/>As they climbed the hill on the further side 
  <lb/>artillery began to boom. Here <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStC" facs="#ms_031_z007">Fleming</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStC" facs="#ms_031_z006">the youth</add> forgot many 
  <lb/>things as he felt a sudden impulse of curio<subst facs="#ms_031_z008"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_031_z008">us</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_031_z008">si</add></subst>ty. He 
  <lb/>scrambled up the bank with a speed that could not 
  <lb/>be acceded by a blood-thirsty man.
  <lb/>He expected a battle-scene.
  <lb/>There were some little fields girted and squeezed 
  <lb/>by a forest. Spread over the grass and in among the 
  <lb/>tree-trunks, he could see knots and waving lines of skir-
  <lb/>mishers who were running hither and thither and firing 
  <lb/>at the landscape. A dark battle-line lay upon a sun-
  <lb/>struck clearing that gleamed orange-color. A flag 
  <lb/>fluttered.
  <lb/>Other regiments floundered up the bank. 
  <lb/>The brigade was formed in line of battle and
  <lb/>, after a pause, started slowly through the woods in 
  <lb/>the rear of the recedeing skirmishers who were 
  <lb/>continually melting into the scene to appear again
</ab><milestone n="3" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>