<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_096"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="placemark" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_096_z007">96</metamark></ab><ab><lb/>tested. Yet they would recieve laurels from tradition. He cried out
  <lb/>bitterly that their crowns were stolen and their robes of glorious
  <lb/>memories were shams. However, he still said that it was a
  <lb/>great pity he was not as they.
  <lb/>A defeat of the army had suggested itself to him as a
  <lb/>means of escape from the consequences of his fall. He con-
  <lb/>sidered<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_096_z009">,</add><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_096_z001">, however, </del> now, however, that it was useless to think of
  <lb/>such a possibility. His education had been<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_096_z002"> </del>that
  <lb/>success for that mighty blue machine was certain; that it
  <lb/>would make victories as a contrivance turns out buttons.
  <lb/>He presently discard ed all his speculations in the other dir-
  <lb/>ection. He returned to the creed of soldiers.
  <lb/>When he percieved again that it was not possible
  <lb/>for the army to be defeated, he tried to be-think him of a
  <lb/>fine tale which he could take back to his regiment and
  <lb/>with it turn the expected shafts of derision .
  <lb/>But, as he mortally feared these shafts, it became impossible
  <lb/>for him to invent a tale which he felt he could trust. He experi-
  <lb/>mented with many schemes but threw them aside one by one as flimsy.
  <lb/>He was quick to see vulnerable places in them all.
  <lb/>Furthermore, he was much afraid that some
  <lb/>arrow of scorn might lay him mentally low before
  <lb/>he could raise his protecting tale.
  <lb/>He run, didn't'e? Oh, my!" He recalled various persons
  <lb/>who would be quite sure to leave him no peace about it.
  <lb/>They would doubtless question him with sneers and
</ab><milestone n="11" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>