<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_071"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_071_z019">71</metamark></ab><ab><lb/>with it. The torn bodies expressed the awful machinery
  <lb/>in which the men had been entangled.
  <lb/>Orderlies and couriers occasionally broke through the
  <lb/>throng in the roadway, scattering wounded men right
  <lb/>and left, galloping on, followed by howls. The mel-
  <lb/>ancholy march was continually disturbed by the messengers
  <lb/>and sometimes by bustling batteries that came swinging and
  <lb/>thumping down upon them, the officiers shouting orders to
  <lb/>clear the way.
  <lb/>There was a tattered man, fouled with dust, blood
  <lb/>and powder-stain from hair to shoes who trudged quietly
  <lb/>at <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_071_z006">Fleming's</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_071_z005">the youth's</add> side. He was listening with eagerness and
  <lb/>much humility to the lurid descriptions of a bearded serjeant.
  <lb/>His lean features wore an expression of awe and admiration.
  <lb/>He was like a listener in a country-store to wondrous tales
  <lb/>told among the <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_071_z007">s</del>sugar-barrels. He eyed the story-teller
  <lb/>with unspeakable wonder. His mouth was a-gape in yokel fashion.
  <lb/>The serjeant, taking note of this, gave pause to his el-
  <lb/>aborate history while he administered a sar<subst facs="#ms_071_z005"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_071_z005">ca</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_071_z005">do</add></subst>nic comment.
  <lb/>"Be keerful, honey, you'll be a-ketchin' flies," he said.
  <lb/><del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_071_z011">At this,</del>The tattered man shrank back, abashed.
  <lb/>After a time, he began to sidle near to <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_071_z014">Fleming</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_071_z013">the youth</add> and
  <lb/>in a diffident way, try to make him a friend. His voice
  <lb/>was gentle as a girl's voice and his eyes were pleading.
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_071_z016">Fleming</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_071_z015">the youth</add> saw with surprise that the soldier had two wounds
  <lb/>, one in the head, bound with a blood-soaked rag and the
  <lb/>other in the arm, making that member dangle like a
  <lb/>broken bough.
  <lb/>After they had walked <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_071_z017">along</del>together for some time,
  <lb/>the tattered man mustered sufficent courage to speak.
  <lb/>"Was pretty good fight, w'a'nt it?" he timidly said.
  </ab>
  <milestone n="8" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>