<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_188"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z041">188.</metamark></ab><ab><lb/>He saw that he was good. He re-called with a thrill of joy
<lb/>the respectful comments of his fellows upon his conduct. He said
<lb/>to himself again the sentence of the insane <del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z020">young</del> lieutenant: "If
<lb/>I had ten thousand wild-cats like you, I could tear th' stomach
<lb/>outa this war in less'n a week." It was a little coronation.
<lb/>Nevertheless, the ghost of his flight from the first engagement
<lb/>appeared to him and danced. Echoes of his <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z021">terrific</del> terrible combat
<lb/>with the arrayed forces of <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z025">nature</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z032">the</add> universe came to his ears. There
<lb/>were small <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z027">spectacles</del> shoutings in his brain about these matters.
<lb/>For a moment, he blushed, and the light of his soul flickered
<lb/>with shame.
<lb/>However, he presently<subst facs="#ms_188_z033"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z033">,</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z033">p</add></subst>rocured an explanation and an
<lb/>ap<subst facs="#ms_188_z036"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z036">a</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z036">o</add></subst>logy. He said that those tempestuous moments were of the
<lb/>wild mistakes and ravings of a novice who did not com-
<lb/>prehend. He had been a mere man railing at a condition
<lb/>but now he was out of it and <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z028">he</del> could see that it had been
<lb/>very proper and just. It had been necessary for him to
<lb/>swallow swords that he might have a better throat for
<lb/>grapes. Fate had in truth, <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z029">been</add><metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z040">^</metamark>kind to him; she had stabbed him
<lb/>with benign purpose and diligently cudgeled him for his own
<lb/>sake. In his rebellion, he had been very portentious, no doubt,
<lb/>and sincere, and anxious for <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z030">the</del> humanity, but now that he
<lb/>stood safe, with no lack of blood, it was suddenly clear to
<lb/>him that he had been wrong not to kiss the knife and bow
<lb/>to the cudgel. He had foolishly squirmed.
<lb/>But the sky would forget. It was true, he admitted,
<lb/>that in the world it was the habit to cry devil at persons who
<lb/>refused to trust what they could not trust, but he thought
<lb/>that perhaps the stars dealt differently. The imperturbable
<lb/>sun shines on insult and worship.
<lb/>As Fleming was thus fraternizing again with nature,
<lb/>a <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_188_z039">p</del> spectre of reproach came to him. There loomed
</ab><milestone n="25" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>