<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><ab><pb facs="#ms_159"/><add place="margin-top" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z084">159</add><lb/>unconquerable thing, there seemed <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z059">to</add> arise a feeling that they
<lb/>had been betrayed. They glowered with bent brows but dan-
<lb/>gerously upon some of the officers, more particularly upon
<lb/>the red-bearded one with the voice of triple brass .
<lb/>However, the rear of the regiment was fringed with
<lb/>men <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z061">who</add> continued to shoot irritably at the advancing foes. They seemed<del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z062">were</del> 
<lb/>resolved to make every trouble. The<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z064">He was still</del> youthful lieuten-
<lb/>ant was perhaps the last man in the disordered mass. His for-
<lb/>gotten back was toward the enemy. He had been shot in the
<lb/>arm. It hung<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z065">,</del> straight and rigid. Occasionally he would 
<lb/>cease to remember it and be about to emphasize an oath 
<lb/>with a sweeping gesture. The multiplied pain caused him
<lb/>to swear with incredi<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z066">a</del>ble power.
<lb/>The youth<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z069">Fleming had</del> went along with slipping, uncertain feet. He kept
<lb/>watchful eyes rear-ward. A scowl of mortification and rage
<lb/>was upon his face. He <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z070">t</del>had thought of a fine revenge upon the 
<lb/>officer who had referred to him and as<add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z071">his</add> fellows as mule-drivers.
<lb/>But he saw that it could not come to pass. His dreams had 
<lb/>collapsed when the mule-drivers, dwindling rapidly, had wavered
<lb/>and hesitated on the little clearing and then had recoiled. And 
<lb/>now the retreat of the mule-drivers was a march of shame 
<lb/>to him.
<lb/>A dagger-pointed gaze from without his blackened <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z072">g</del>face
<lb/>was held toward the enemy but his greater hatred was rivetted
<lb/>upon the man, who, not knowing him, had called him a mule-
<lb/>driver. <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z073">S</del>When he knew that he and his comrades had failed to do
<lb/>anything in successful ways that might bring <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z074">the</del><add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z089">the little</add> pangs of a 
<lb/>kind of remorse upon the,officer, <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_159_z075">Fleming</del>the youth allowed the rage of the 
<lb/>baffled to possess him. This cold officer upon a monument who
<lb/>dropped <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z077">his</del>epithets <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z078">coldly</del>unconcernedly down, would be finer as a dead man,
<lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_159_z080">Fleming</del>he thought. So grievous did he think it that he could never 
<lb/>possess the secret right to taunt truly<del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z082">.</del> in <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_159_z083">return.</del>answer. </ab>
<milestone n="21" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>