<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_174"/>
<ab>
  <lb/>On a slope to the left, there was a long row of guns, 
  <lb/>gruff and maddened, denouncing the enemy who down through
  <lb/>the woods were forming for another attack in the pitiless 
  <lb/>monotony of conflicts. The round, red discharges from the guns
  <lb/>made a crimson flare and a high, thick smoke. Occasional
  <lb/>glimpses could be caught of <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z015">the</del>groups of the toiling artillerymen.
  <lb/>In the rear of this row of guns stood a house, calm and
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z012">wide</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z012">white</add>, amid bursting shells. A congregation of horses, tied to
  <lb/>a long railing, were tugging frenziedly at their bridles. Men
  <lb/>were running hither and thither.
  <lb/>The <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z012">se</del> detached battle between the four regiments lasted
  <lb/>for some time.There chanced to be no interference and they 
  <lb/>settled their dispute by themselves. They struck savagely and
  <lb/>powerfully at each other for a period of minutes and then the
  <lb/>lighter-hued regiments <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z020">dr</del>faltered and drew back, leaving the
  <lb/>dark, blue lines, shouting. Fleming could see the two flags
  <lb/>shaking and laughing amid the smoke-remnants.
  <lb/>Presently, there was a stillness, pregnant with meaning. 
  <lb/>The blue lines shifted and <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z022">settled</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z022">changed</add>a trifle and stared expectantly 
  <lb/>at the silent woods and fields before them. The hush was 
  <lb/>solomn and church-like <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z023">.</del>, save for a distant battery that, evi
  <lb/>dently unable to remain quiet sent a faint rolling thunder over
  <lb/>the ground. It irritated, like the noises of <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z024">nw</del> unimpressed boy<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z042">s.</add>
  <lb/><del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z026">boy. It would</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z026">The men imagined that it would prevent their pearched ears</add><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z028">of the men</del> from 
  <lb/>hearing the first words of the new <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z029">new</add> battle.
  <lb/>Of a sudden, the guns on the slope roared out a message of
  <lb/>warning. A spluttering sound had begun in the woods. It swelled
  <lb/>with amazing speed to a profound clamor that involved the earth 
  <lb/>in noises. The<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z033">clattering</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z033">splitting</add> crashes swept along the lines until an inter
  <lb/>minable roar was developed. <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_174_z036">I</del>To those in the midst of it, be
  <lb/>came a din fitted to the universe. It was the whirring and thumping
  <lb/>of gigantic machinery, complications among the smaller stars.</ab>
<milestone n="23" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>