<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_141"/>
<ab>
  <lb/>The youth cried out savagely at this statement. He crouched be
  <lb/>hind a little tree, with his eyes burning balefully and his teeth
  <lb/>set in a cur-like snarl. The awkward bandage was still about 
  <lb/>his head and, upon it, over his wound there was a spot of dry
  <lb/>blood. His hair was wondrously towsled and some strag
  <lb/>gling, moving locks hung over the cloth of the bandage down 
  <lb/>toward his forehead. His jacket and shirt were open at the neck
  <lb/>and exposed his young, bronzed neck. There could be seen
  <lb/>spasmodic gulpings at his throat.
  <lb/>His fingers twined nervously about his rifle. He wished
  <lb/>that it was an engine of annihilating power. He felt that he and his 
  <lb/>companions were being taunted and derided from sincere convictions
  <lb/>that they were poor and puny. 
  <lb/>His knowledge of his inability to take vengeance for it made his
  <lb/>rage into a dark and stormy spectre that possessed him and
  <lb/>made him dream of abominable cruelties. The tormentors were 
  <lb/>flies sucking insolently at his blood and he thought that he
  <lb/>would have given his life for a revenge of seeing their faces
  <lb/>in pitiful plights.
  <lb/>The winds of battle had swept all about the regiment
  <lb/>until the one rifle, instantly followed by brothers, flashed in
  <lb/>it's front. A moment later, the regiment roared forth it's sud
  <lb/>den and valiant retort. A dense wall of smoke settled slowly 
  <lb/>down. It was furiously slit and slashed by the knife-
  <lb/>like fire from the rifles.
  <lb/>To the youth, the fighters were like animals tossed for
  <lb/>a death-struggle into a dark pit. There was a sen
  <lb/>sation that he and fellows, at bay, were pushing back, always
  <lb/>pushing fierce onslaughts of creatures who were slippery.
  <lb/>Their beams of crimson seemed to get no purchase upon the
  <lb/>bodies of their foes; the latter seemed to evade them with 
  <lb/>ease and come through, between, around and about, with 
  <lb/>unopposed skill.
</ab><milestone n="18" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>