<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_185"/><ab><add place="below" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_185_z026">185</add>, <add place="below" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_185_z021">XXV</add><lb/>The roarings that had stretched in a long line of sound across 
<lb/>the face of the forest began to grow intermittent and weaker. The stentorian <metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_185_z009"/><metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_185-0011"/>
<lb/>speeches of the artillery continued in some distant encounter but the 
<lb/> <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_185_z005">cry</del> crashes of the musketry had almost ceased. Fleming and his 
<lb/>friend, of a sudden <del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_185_z006">lookeding</del> up, feeling a deadened form of dis-
<lb/>tress at the waning of these noises which had become a part of 
<lb/>life. They could see changes going on among the troops. There were 
<lb/>marchings this way and that way. A battery wheeled leisurely. 
<lb/>On the crest of a small hill was the thick gleam of many de-
<lb/>parting muskets.
<lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_185_z022">FlemingThe</del>youth arose. "Well, what now, I wonder," he said. <del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_185_z008">DyBy</del> his
<lb/>tone, he seemed to be preparing to resent some new monstrosity in
<lb/>the way of dins and smashes. He shaded his eyes with his grimey
<lb/>hand and gazed over the field.
<lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_185_z009">WilsonHis</del>friend also arose and stared. "I bet we're gain' t' git along
<lb/>outa this an' back over th' river," said he.
<lb/>"Well, I <del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_185_z027">swan</del>," said the <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_185-0010">youthFleming</del>.
<lb/>They waited, watching. Within a little while, the regiment 
<lb/>recieved orders to retrace it's way. The men got up grunting from the 
<lb/>grass, regretting the soft <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_185_z012">reposesinthegrass</del> behind the rails. They jerked their
<lb/>stiffened legs and stretched their arms over their heads. One man
<lb/>swore as he rubbed his eyes. They all groaned. "Oh, Lord." They
<lb/>had as many objections to this change as they would have had
<lb/>to a proposal for a new battle.
<lb/>They tramped slowly back over the field across which they
<lb/>had run in a mad scamper. The fence, deserted, resumed with
<lb/>it's careening posts and disjointed bars, an air of quiet rural
<lb/>depravity. Beyond it, there lay spread a few corpses. Conspic-
<lb/>uous, was the contorted body of the color-bearer in grey whose
</ab><milestone n="25" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>