<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_152"/><ab>split the cammand and scattered it into detached clusters.
  <lb/>The youth, light-footed was unconsciously in advance. His 
  <lb/>eyes still kept note of the clump of trees. From all places near 
  <lb/>it the clannish yell of the enemy could be heard. The little 
  <lb/>flames of rifles leaped from it. The song of the bullets was 
  <lb/>in the air and shells snarled among the tree-tops. One tum-
  <lb/>bled directly into the middle of a hurrying group and ex-
  <lb/>ploded in crimson fury. There was an instant's spectacle of 
  <lb/>a man, almost over it, throwing up his hands to shield his eyes.
  <lb/>Other men, punched by bullets, fell in grotesque agonies. 
  <lb/>The regiment left a coherent trail of bodies.
  <lb/>They had passed into a clearer atmosphere. There was 
  <lb/>an effect like a revelation in the new appearance of the 
  <lb/>landscape. Some men working madly at a battery were 
  <lb/>plain to them and the opposing infantry's lines were de-
  <lb/>fined by the grey walls and fringes of smoke.
  <lb/>It seemed to the youth that he saw everything. Each 
  <lb/>blade of the green grass was bold and clear. He thought that 
  <lb/>he was aware of every change in the thin, transparent va-
  <lb/>por that floated idly m sheets. The brown or grey 
  <lb/>trunks of the trees showed each roughness of their surfaces. 
  <lb/>And the men of the regiment, with their starting eyes and 
  <lb/>sweating faces, running madly, or falling, as if thrown 
  <lb/>headlong, to queer, heaped up corpses, all were comprehended. 
  <lb/>His mind took a mechanical but firm impressions, so that, after-
  <lb/>ward, everything was pictured and explained to him, save 
  <lb/>why he himself was there.
  <lb/>But there was a frenzy made from this furious rush. 
  <lb/>The men, pitching forward insanely, had burst into cheer-
  <lb/>ings, mob-like and barbaric, but tuned in strange 
  <lb/>keys that can arouse the dullard and the stoic. It made 
  <lb/>a mad enthusiasm that, it seemed, would be incapable of
</ab><milestone n="20" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>