<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_151"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z025">XX</metamark></ab><ab> 151
<lb/>
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_151_z001">Flemming</del><add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_151_z002">The youth</add> stared at the <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z003">foliage</del>land in front of him. Its foliages
  <lb/>now seemed to veil powers and horrors. He was unaware of the ma-
  <lb/>chinery of orders that started the charge, although from the cor-
  <lb/>ners of his eyes, he saw an officer, who looked like a boy a-
  <lb/>horse<add place="margin-right" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z010">back</add>, come galloping, waving his hat. Suddenly, he felt
  <lb/>a straining and heaving among the men. The line fell slowly
  <lb/>forward like a toppling wall and with a convulsive gasp
  <lb/>that was intended for a cheer<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z012">.</del><add place="margin-right" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z013">,</add> the regiment began it's
  <lb/>journey. <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_151_z004">flemming</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_151_z005">The youth</add> was pushed and jostled for a moment
  <lb/>before he understood the movement at all but directly he
  <lb/>lunged <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_151_z008">forward</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_151_z007">ahead</add> and began to run.
  <lb/>He fixed his eye upon a distant and prominent clump of
  <lb/>trees where he had concluded the enemy w<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStD" facs="#ms_151-0015">h</del>ere to be <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z009">with</del>met,
  <lb/>and he ran toward it as toward a gaol. He had believed,
  <lb/>throughout that it was <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z016">a</add>mere question of getting over an
  <lb/>unpleasant matter as quickly as possible and he ran des-
  <lb/>perately as if pursued for <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z017">a</add> murder. His face was drawn hard
  <lb/>and tight with the stress of his endeavor. His <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z018">eyes</add> were fixed in a
  <lb/>lurid glare. And with his <subst facs="#ms_151_z019"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z019">soiled</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z019"/></subst> and disordered dress, his red
  <lb/>and inflamed features surmounted by the dingy rag with it's
  <lb/>spot of blood, his wildly swinging rifle and banging ac-
  <lb/>coutrements, he looked to be an insane soldier.
  <lb/>As the regiment swung from it's position out into a
  <lb/>cleared space, the woods and thickets before it, awakened. Yellow
  <lb/>flames <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z023">sl</del>leaped toward it from <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_151_z022">eve</del>many directions. The forest made a tremendous objection.
  <lb/>The line lurched straight for a moment. Then the right
  <lb/>wing swung forward; it in turn was surpassed by the left.
  <lb/>Afterward the centre careered to the front until the regiment
  <lb/>was a wedge-shaped mass but an instant later, the oppos-
  <lb/>ition of the bushes, trees and uneven places on the ground
</ab><milestone n="20" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>