<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><ab><pb facs="#ms_098-104"/><ab><lb/>98-104 XII
  <lb/>The column that had butted stoutly at the <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_098-104_z003">obsta</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z001">obstacles</add> in the roadway was
  barely out of <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z004">Fleming's</del> <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z005">the youth's</add> sight before he saw dark waves of men come sweeping
  out of the woods and down through the fields. He knew at once that
  the steel fibres had been washed from their hearts. They were bursting
  from their coats and their equipments as from entanglements. They
  charged down upon him like terrified buffaloes.
  <lb/>Behind them, blue smoke curled and clouded <restore change="mStA" hand="#SC" facs="#ms_098-104_z030">o</restore>above the tree-tops
  and through the thickets he could sometimes see a distant pink glare.
  The voices of the cannon were clamoring in interminable chorus.
  <lb/><del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z006">Fleming</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z007">The youth</add> was horror-struckstricken. He stared in agony and amazement.
  He forgot that he was engaged in combating the universe. He threw
  aside his mental pamphlets on the philosophy of the retreated and rules
  for the guidance of the <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z008">damned</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z009">doomed</add>. He lost concer<del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z032">r</del>n for himself.
  <lb/>The fight was lost. The dragons were coming with invincible<del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z033">.</del>
  strides. The army, helpless in the matted thickets,
  <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z011">was going to be swallowed</del> and blinded by the overhanging
  night, was going to be swallowed. War,the red animal, war,
  the blood-swollen god, would have bloated fill.
  <lb/>Within him, something bade to cry out. He had the
  impulse to make a rallying speech, to sing a battle-hymn but
  he could only get his tongue to call into the air: "Why--why--
  what--what's th' matter?"
  <lb/>Soon he was in the midst of them<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z017">. tT</add>hey were leaping and 
  scampering all about him. Their blanched faces shone in the dusk.
  They seemed, for the most part, to be very burly men.
  <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z012">They</del> <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z019">Fleming</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z014">The youth</add> turned from one to another <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z015">of them</add> as they galloped
  along. His incoherent questions were lost. They were heedless
  of his appeals. <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z015">and</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z016">They</add> did not seem to see him.
  <lb/><add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStA" facs="#ms_098-104_z022"/>They sometimes gabbled insanely. One huge man was
</ab></ab></div></body></text>