<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_074"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_074_z011"/></ab><ab><lb/>IX<lb/><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_074_z013">The youth</add><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_074_z014">Fleming</del><metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStE" facs="#ms_074_z012">^</metamark> fell back in the procession until the tattered <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z015">man</del>
  <lb/>soldier was not in sight. Then he started to walk on with others.
  <lb/>But he was amid wounds. The mob of men was bleeding.
  <lb/>Because of the tattered soldier's question, he now felt that his
  <lb/>shame could be viewed. He was continually casting side-long
  <lb/>glances to see if the men were contemplating the letters of
  <lb/>guilt he felt burned into his brow.
  <lb/>At times, he regarded the wounded soldiers in an envious
  <lb/>way. He concieved <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z017">men</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z016">persons</add> with torn bodies to be peculiarly
  <lb/>happy. He wished that he, too, had a wound, a little
  <lb/><del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z018">woun</del> red badge of courage.
  <lb/>The spectral soldier was at his side like a stalk-
  <lb/>ing reproach. The m<subst facs="#ms_074_z020"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z020">e</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z020">a</add></subst>n's eyes were still fixed in a stare
  <lb/>into the unknown. His grey, apalling face had attracted
  <lb/>attention in the crowd and men, slowing to his dreary
  <lb/>pace, were walking with him. They were discussing his
  <lb/>plight, questioning him and giving him advice. In a
  <lb/>dogged way, he repelled them, signing to them to go on
  <lb/>and leave him alone. <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z021">There could be seen a certain</del>
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z022">stiffness in the</del>The shadows of his face were deepening 
  <lb/>and his tight lips seemed holding in check the moan of
  <lb/>great despair. There could be seen a certain stiffness in
  <lb/>the movements of his body as if he were taking infinite
  <lb/>care not to arouse the passions of his wounds. <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z023">And as</del>
  <lb/>As he went on, he seemed always looking for a place, like
  <lb/>one who goes to choose a grave.
  <lb/>Something in the gesture of the man as he waved the
  <lb/>bloody and pitying soldiers <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_074_z024">aside</del>away, made <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_074_z026">Fleming</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_074_z025">the youth</add> start as if
</ab><milestone n="9" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>