<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_070"/>
<ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_070_z022">70</metamark><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_070_z022"/></ab><ab>
  <lb/>One was marching with an air imitative of some sublime
  <lb/>drum-major. Upon his features was an unholy mixture of 
  <lb/>merriment and agony. As he marched he sang isa bit of 
  <lb/>doggerel in a high and quavering voice.
  <lb/>"Sing a song 'a vic'try"
  <lb/>"A pocketful 'a bullets"
  <lb/>"Five an' twenty dead men"
  <lb/>"Baked in a--pie."
  <lb/>Parts of the procession limped and staggered to this tune.
  <lb/>Another had the grey seal of death already upon his 
  <lb/>face. His lips were curled in hard lines and his teeth were clenched. His hands were bloody from where he had pressed 
  <lb/>them upon his wound. He seemed to be awaiting the moment 
  <lb/>when he should pitch headlong. He stalked like the <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_070_z013">grim</del> 
  <lb/>spectre of a soldier, his eyes <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_070_z013">buring</del>burning with the power of a stare 
  <lb/>into the unknown.
  <lb/>There were some who proceeded sullenly, full of anger at 
  <lb/>their wounds and ready to turn upon anything as an obscure cause.
  <lb/>An officer was carried along by two privates. He was peevish. 
  <lb/>"Don't joggle so, Johnson, yeh fool," he cried. "Think m'leg is 
  <lb/>made of iron? If yeh can't carry me decent, put me down 
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_070_z013">and</del>an' let <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_070_z013">somerels</del>some one else do it."
  <lb/>He bellowed at the tottering crowd who blocked the quick march 
  <lb/>of his bearers. "Say, make way there, can't yeh? Make way, dickens take it all."
  <lb/>They sulkily parted and went to the roadsides. As he was
  <lb/>carried <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_070_z013">it</del>past they made part remarks to him. when he raged
  <lb/>and threatened them, they told him to be damned.
  <lb/>The shoulder of one of the tramping bearers
  <lb/>oked heavily against the <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_070_z013">spectralshoulder</del> spectral soldier who
  <lb/>staring into the unknown.
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_070_z013">Fleming</del>The youth joined this crowd and marched along
</ab><milestone n="8" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>