<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_050"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_050_z015">50</metamark></ab><ab><lb/>the position of a tired man, resting<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_050_z019">,</add><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_050_z019">.</del> but upon his face there
  <lb/>was an astonished and sorrowful <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStD" facs="#ms_050_z002">air</del><subst><del rend="overwrite pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStD" facs="#ms_050_z001">look</del><add place="above" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStF" facs="#ms_050_z024">look</add></subst> as if he thought some
  <lb/>friend had done him an ill turn. The babbling man was
  <lb/>grazed by a shot that made the blood stream widely down
  <lb/>his face. He clapped both hands to his head. "Oh," he said
  <lb/>and ran. Another grunted suddenly as if he been struck by a
  <lb/>club in the stomach. He sat down and gazed ruefully. In his
  <lb/>eyes there was mute, indefinite reproach. Further up the line
  <lb/>a man, standing behind a tree, had had his knee-joint
  <lb/>splintered by a ball. Immediately, he had dropped his rifle
  <lb/>and gripped the tree with both arms. And there he re-
  <lb/>mained, clinging desperately, and crying for assistance that
  <lb/>he might <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_050_z006">leave loo</del> withdraw his hold upon the tree.
  <lb/>At last, an exultant yell went along the quivering line. 
  <lb/>The firing dwindled from an uproar to a last vindictive pop-
  <lb/>ping. As the smoke slowly eddied away, <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_050_z008">Fleming</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_050_z007">the youth</add> saw that the
  <lb/>charge had been repulsed. The enemy were scattered into re-
  <lb/>luctant groups. He saw a man climb to the top of the fence,
  <lb/>straddle the rail and fire a parting shot. The waves had re-
  <lb/>ceded, leaving bits of dark debris upon the ground.
  <lb/>Some in the regiment began to whoop frenziedly. Many
  <lb/>were silenc<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStD" facs="#ms_050_z020">e</del>. Apparently, they were trying to contemplate themselves.
  <lb/>After the <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_050_z009">river</del> fever had left his veins, <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_050_z011">Fleming</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_050_z010">the youth</add> thought
  <lb/>that at last he was going to suffocate. He became aware of the
  <lb/>foul atmosphere in which he had been struggling. He was grimey
  <lb/>and dripping like a laborer in a foundry. He grasped his
  <lb/>canteen and took a long swallow of the w<del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_050_z022">a</del><subst><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_050_z022">a</add></subst>rmed water.
  <lb/>A sentence with variations went up and down the line.
  <lb/>"Well, we've helt'em back. We've helt'em back--derned if we
  <lb/>haven't." The men said it with blissfully, leering at each
  <lb/>other with dirty smiles.
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_050_z013">Fleming</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_050_z012">The youth</add> turned to look behind him and off to the right <add place="inline" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_050_z023">and</add>
</ab><milestone n="5" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>