<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_062"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_062_z020">62</metamark></ab><ab> <lb/>knowledge. He felt a great anger against his comrades. He knew
<lb/>it could be proven that they had been fools.
<lb/>He wondered what they would remark when later
<lb/>he appeared in camp. His mind heard howls of derision.
<lb/>Their density would not enable them to understand <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z001">fin</del>his
<lb/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z004">er and deeper</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z005">sharper</add> point of view.
<lb/>He began to pity himself acutely. He was ill-used. He
<lb/>was trodden beneath the feet of an iron injustice. He had
<lb/>proceeded with wisdom and from the most righteous motives un-
<lb/>der Heaven's blue only to be frustrated by hateful circumstances.
<lb/>A dull, animal-like rebellion against his fellows,
<lb/>war<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z017">,</del> in the abstract, and fate, grew within him. He sham-
<lb/>bled along with <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z015">bowed</add> head, his brain in a tumult of agony and
<lb/>despair. When he looked loweringly up, quivering at each
<lb/>sound, his eyes had the expression of those of a criminal
<lb/>who thinks his guilt little and his punishment great and
<lb/>knows that he can find no words; who, through his suf-
<lb/>fering, thinks that he peers into the core of things and see
<lb/>that the judgment of m<subst facs="#ms_062_z012"><del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z012">e</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z012">a</add></subst>n is thistle-down in wind.
<lb/>He went from the fields into a thicks woods as if
<lb/>resolved to bury himself. He wished to get out of hearing of the
<lb/>crackling shots which were to him like voices.
<lb/>The ground was cluttered with vines and bushes and
<lb/>the trees grew close and spread out like bouquets. He was ob-
<lb/>liged to force his way with much noise. The creepers, catching
<lb/>against his legs, cried out harshly as their sprays were torn
<lb/>from the barks of trees. The swishing saplings tried to
<lb/>make known his presence to the world. He could not
<lb/>conciliate the forest. As he made <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z006">its</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z007">his</add> way, it <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z008">seemed</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z009">was</add>
<lb/>always calling out protestations. When he separated
<lb/>embraces of trees and vines, the disturbed foliages
<lb/>waved their arms and turned their face-leaves
<lb/><del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_062_z010">toward him.</del>
</ab>
<milestone n="7" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>