<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><ab><pb facs="#ms_107"/>
<ab>
  <lb/>
  <lb/>curve toward a gap in a fence. The officer was making 
  <lb/>excited motions with a gauntleted hand. The guns followed
  <lb/>the teams with an air of unwillingness <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z001">.</del> of being dragged by the heels.
  <lb/>Some officers of the scattered infantry were cursing and 
  <lb/>railing like fish-wives. Their scolding voices could be heard 
  <lb/>above the din. Into the unspeakable <add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z001">jumble</add> in the road-way, rode a 
  <lb/>squadron of cavalry. The faded yellow of their facings 
  <lb/>shone bravely. There was a mighty altercation.
  <lb/>The artillery were assembling as if for a conference.
  <lb/>The blue haze of evening was upon the fields. The lines 
  <lb/>of forest were long purple shadows. One cloud lay along the west<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z004">-</add>
  <lb/>ern sky partly smothering the red.
  <lb/>As <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z021"/>the youth left the scene behind him, he heard the guns sud<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z006">-</add>
  <lb/>denly roar out. He imagined them shaking in black rage. They 
  <lb/>belched and roared like brass devils guarding a gate. The 
  <lb/>soft air was filled with the tremendous remonstrance. With 
  <lb/>it came the shattering peal of opposing infantry. Turning to
  <lb/>look behind him, he could see sheets of orange light illu-<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z007"/>
  <lb/>mine the shadowy distance. There were subtle and sudden 
  <lb/>lightnings in the far air. At times, he thought he could 
  <lb/>see heaving masses of men.
  <lb/>He hurried on in the dusk. The day had faded until 
  <lb/>he could barely distinguish place for his feet. The purple dark-<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z010"/>
  <lb/>ness was filled with men who lectured and jabbered. Some-<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z012"/>
  <lb/>times, he could see them gesticulating against the blue, 
  <lb/>and sombre sky. There seemed to be a great ruck of men
  <lb/>and munitions spread about in the forest and in the 
  <lb/>fields. The little narrow road-way now lay <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z025">like</del> lifeless. <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z017">torrent</del> There were over-turned wagons like sun-dried 
  <lb/>boulders. The bed of the former torrent was choked with the bodies of horses<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z018">.</del> and <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_107_z019">the</del> splintered parts of war-
  <lb/>machines.
</ab><milestone n="13" unit="chapter"/></ab></div></body></text>