<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_136"/><ab><lb/>In his reply, Wilson'sthe friend's voice was stern. "'A course not," he 
  <lb/>said,. "No man dare say we don't fight like th' devil. No man
  <lb/>will ever dare say it. Th' boys fight like devilhell-roosters.
  <lb/>But still-still, we don't have no luck."
  <lb/>"Well, then, if we fight like theth' devil an' don't ever
  <lb/>hawhip, it must be th' general'general's fault," said Flemingthe youth
  <lb/>grandly and decisively. "AndAn' I don't see noany sense in
  <lb/>fightingfightin' andan' fightingfightin' andan' fightingfightin', yit allusyet always lossinglossin' through
  <lb/>some derned oldol' lunkhead of 'a general."
  <lb/>A sarcastic man who was tramping at Fleming'sthe youth's
  <lb/>side, then spoke lazily. "Mebbe yeh think yeh fit th' hull
  <lb/>battle yestirday, FlemingFlemin'," he remarked.
  <lb/>The speech pierced the youth.
  <lb/>He was reduced toInward, he was reduced to abjectionsan abject pulp by these
  <lb/>chance words. His legs quaked privately. He cast a frigh-
  <lb/>tened glance at the sarcastic man.
  <lb/>"Why, no," he hastened to say in a conciliatory voice,
  <lb/>"I don't think I foughtfit theth' hullwhole battle yestirday."
  <lb/>But the other seemed innocent of any deeper mean-
  <lb/>ing. Apparently, he had no information.
  <lb/>"Oh", he said as if relieved, "I thought maybe you did."It was merely his habit.
  <lb/>"Oh," he merelyreplied in the same tone of calm derision.
  <lb/>FlemingThe youth, nevertheless, felt a threat. His mind shrank
  <lb/>from going near to the danger and, thereafter, he was silent.
  <lb/>The significance of the sarcastic man's words took from
  <lb/>him all moodsloud moods that mightwould make him appear prom-
  <lb/>inent. He became suddenly a modest man.
  <lb/>There was low-toned andtalk among the troops.
  <lb/>The officers were impatient and snappy, their countenances
  <lb/>clouded with the tales of misfortune. The troops, sifting
  <lb/>through the forest, were sullen. In Fleming's company
  <lb/>once, a man's laugh rang out. A dozen soldiers
  <lb/>The officers were impatient and snappy, their countenances
  <lb/>clouded with the tales of misfortune. The troops, sifting
  <lb/>through the forest, were sullen. In Fleming's company
  <lb/>once, a man's laugh rang out. A dozen soldiers
</ab><milestone n="17" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>