<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><ab><pb facs="#ms_106"/><ab><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_106_z016"><lb/>Fleming's</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_106_z049">The youth's</add> fingers had turned to paste upon the other's arm. The energy
<lb/>was smitten from his muscles. He saw the flaming wings of lightning
<lb/>flash before his vision. There was a deafening<del rend="inkblot ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z022"/> rumble of thunder
<lb/><add place="margin-left" rend="no-caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z018">with</add>in his <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z019">ears</del> head.
  <lb/>Suddenly his legs seemed to die. He sank writheing to the
<lb/>ground. He tried to arise. In his efforts against the numbing
<lb/>pain he was like a man wrestling with a creature of the air.
  <lb/>There was a sinister struggle.
  <lb/>Sometimes, he would achieve a position half-erect, battle with
<lb/>the air for a moment, and then fall again, <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z061">his <metamark place="inline" function="caret" rend="ink" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z062">^</metamark><add place="above" rend="caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z063">weak</add> fingers</del>
<lb/>grabbing at the grass. His face was of a clammy pallor. Deep
<lb/>groans were wrenched from him .
  <lb/>At last, with a twisting movement, he got upon his hands
<lb/>and knees and from thence, like a babe trying to walk, to his
<lb/>feet. Pressing <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z051">his</add> <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z028">both</del> his hands to his <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z026">head</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z052">temples</add>, he went lurching over
<lb/>the grass.
  <lb/>He fought an intense battle with his body. His dulled
<lb/>senses wished him to swoon and he opposed them stubbornly, his
<lb/>mind portraying unknown dangers and mutilations if <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z029">sh</del> he
<lb/>should fall upon the field. He went,<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z030">forward Conklin</del> <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z053">tall soldier</add>-fashion.
<lb/>He imagined secluded spots where he could fall and be un
<lb/>molested. To reach one, he strove against the tide of his pain.
<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z031">He put his hand to the Once he timidly touch</del>
  <lb/>Once, he put his hand to the top of his head and timidly
<lb/>touched the wound. The scratching pain of the contact made him
<lb/>draw a long breath through his clenched teeth. His fingers
<lb/>were dabbled with blood. He regarded them with a fixed stare.
  <lb/>Around him, he could hear the grumble of jolt<add place="margin-right" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z033">ed</add>
<lb/>cannon <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z039">batteries</del> as the scurrving horses were lashed toward
<lb/>the front. Once, a young officer on a be-splashed charger
<lb/>nearly ran him down. He turned and watched the mass
<lb/>of guns, men and horses sweeping <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_106_z040">through</del> in a wide
</ab><milestone n="13" unit="chapter"/></ab></div></body></text>