<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><ab><pb facs="#ms_108"/>  <lb/>It had come to pass that his wound pained him but
  <lb/>little. He was afraid to move rapidly, however, for a 
  <lb/>dread of disturbing it. He held his head very still and
  <lb/>took many precautions against stumbling. He was filled 
  <lb/>with anxiety and his face was pinched and drawn in 
  <lb/>anticipation of the pain of any sudden mistake of his
  <lb/>feet in the gloom.
  <lb/>His thoughts, as he walked, fixed intently upon his
  <lb/>hurt. There was a cool, liquid feeling about it and he 
  <lb/>imagined blood moving slowly down under his hair. His head
  <lb/>seemed swollen to a size that made <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_108_z001">his neck</del> him think
  <lb/>his neck to be inadequate.
  <lb/>The new silence of his wound made much worri-
  <lb/>ment. The little, blistering voices of pain that had called 
  <lb/>out from his scalp, were, he thought, definite in their
  <lb/>expression of danger. By them, he believed that he could
  <lb/>measure his plight. But when they remained ominously
  <lb/>silent, he became frightened and imagined terrible fing-
  <lb/>ers that clutched into his brain.
  <lb/>Amidst it, he began to reflect upon various incidents and
  <lb/>conditions of the past. He bethought him of certain meals his 
  <lb/>mother had cooked at home, in which those dishes of which
  <lb/>he was particularly fond had occupied prominent positions.
  <lb/>He saw the spread table. The pine walls of the kitchen 
  <lb/>were glowing in the warm light from the stove. Too, he re-
  <lb/>membered how he and his companions used to go from the
  <lb/>schoolhouse to the bank of a shaded pool. He saw his
  <lb/>clothes in disorderly array upon the grass of the bank. He 
  <lb/>felt the swash of the fragrant water upon his body. 
  <lb/>The leaves ot the over-hanging maple rustled with mel-
  <lb/>ody in the wind of youthful summer.
</ab><milestone n="13" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>