<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#ms_155"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="mStA" facs="#ms_155_z004">155.</metamark></ab><ab><lb/>painfully forward until an open space interposed between them and 
  <lb/>the lurid lines. Here, crouching and cowering behind some tree<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_155_z041">s</add>,
  <lb/>the men clung with desperation as if threatened by a wave. They
  <lb/>looked wild-eyed, and as if amazed, at this furious dis-
  <lb/>turbance they had stirred. In the storm, there was an iron-
  <lb/>ical expression of their importance. The faces of the men,
  <lb/>too, <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_155_z008">could be seen</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_155_z007">showed a lack</add> of a certain feeling of responsibility for 
  <lb/>being there. It was as if they had been driven. It was
  <lb/>the dominant animal failing to remember in the<del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStB" facs="#ms_155_z011">critical</del> 
  <lb/>supreme moments, the forceful causes of various superficial
  <lb/>qualities. The whole affair seemed incomprehensible to many 
  <lb/>of them.
  <lb/>As they halted thus, the <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_155_z012">youthful</del>lieutenant again began to 
  <lb/>bellow profanely. Regardless of the vindictive threats of the bul-
  <lb/>lets, he went about^ coaxing, berating and bedamning. His lips, that 
  <lb/>were habitually in a soft and child-like curve, were now writhed
  <lb/>into unholy contortions. He swore by all possible dieeities.
  <lb/>"Once, he grabbed Flemingthe youth by the arm. "Come aon, yeh lunk-
  <lb/>head," he roared. "Come on. We'll all git killed if we
  <lb/>stay here. We've o'ny got t' go across that lot. An' then--"
  <lb/>The remainder of his idea disappeared in a blue haze of curses.
  <lb/>Fleming^The youth stretched forth his arm. "Cross there?" His 
  <lb/>mouth was puckered in doubt and awe.
  <lb/>"Cer'ly! Jest 'cross th' lot! We can't stay here," screamed 
  <lb/>the lieutenant. In his frenzyhHe poked his face close to Flemingthe youth
  <lb/>and waved his bandaged hand. "Come on.!" Presently, he 
  <lb/>grappled with him as if for a wrestling bout. It was as if
  <lb/>he planned to drag Flemingthe youth by the ear on to the assault.
  <lb/>The private felt a sudden unspeakable indignation a-
  <lb/>gainst his officer. He wrenched fiercely and shook him off.
  <lb/>"Come on yerself, then," he yelled. There was a bitter 
  <lb/>challenge in his voice.
  <lb/>They galloped together down the regimental front.The<add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z002"/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z001"/>
  <lb/>friend<add place="margin-left" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z003"/> scrambled after them. In front of the colors, the three men
  <lb/>began to bawl. "Come on! Come on!" They danced<subst facs="#ms_156_z005"><del rend="overwrite pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z005"/><add place="inline" rend="pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z005"/></subst> and 
  <lb/>gyrated like tortured savages.
  <lb/>The flag, obedient to these appeals, bended it's glittering
  <lb/>form and swept toward them. The men wavered in indecision
  <lb/>for a moment and then with a long, wailful cry, the<subst facs="#ms_156_z007"><del rend="overwrite pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z007"/><add place="inline" rend="pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z007"/></subst> delap
  <lb/>itated regiment surged forward and began it's new journey.
  <lb/>Over the field went the <del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z008"/><add place="above" rend="no-caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z009"/><del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z010"/><add place="above" rend="no-caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z011"/><add place="above" rend="no-caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z013"/>scurrying mass. It was a handful
  <lb/>of men splattered into the faces of the enemy. Toward it in
  <lb/>stantly sprang the yellow tongues. A vast quantity of blue smoke
  <lb/>hung before them. A mighty banging made ears valuless.
  <lb/>The youth<del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z014"><add place="above" rend="no-caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z015"> ran like a madman to reach the woods</add></del>
  <lb/>before a bullet could discover him. He ducked his head low
  <lb/>like a foot-ball player.<del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z018"/> In his haste, his eyes almost
  <lb/>closed and the scene was a wild blur. Pulsating saliva
  <lb/>stood at the corners of his mouth.
  <lb/>Within him, as he hurled himself forward, was born a
  <lb/>love, a despairing fondness for this flag which was near
  <lb/>him. It was a creation of beauty and invulnerability. It
  <lb/>was a goddess, radiant, that bended it's form with an im
  <lb/>perious gesture to him. It was a woman, red and white,
  <lb/>hating and loving, that called him with<add place="above" rend="no-caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z022"/> the voice of his hopes.
  <lb/>Because no harm could come to it, he endowed it with
  <lb/>power. He kept near as if it could be a saver of<del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="mStE" facs="#ms_156_z021"/>
  <lb/>lives and an imploring cry went from his mind.
  <lb/>In the mad scramble, he was aware that the
  <lb/>color-serjeant flinched suddenly as if struck by a blud
  <lb/>geon. He faltered and then became motionless, save
  <lb/>for his quivering knees.
</ab><milestone n="20" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>