<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_50"/><ab>50<lb/>The sound of the footsteps behind him gave him a
  <lb/>certain, <add place="above" rend="caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_50_z005">meagre</add> relief. The first clutchings of the dragons would
  <lb/>be <subst facs="#rboc-d_50_z004"><del rend="pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_50_z004">uponof</del><add place="inline" rend="pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_50_z004"/></subst> the men <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_50_z002">who</del> were following him. He 
  <lb/>displayed the zeal of a sprinter in his purpose to keep
  <lb/>them in the rear<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_50_z003"/>. There was a race.
  <lb/>Shells were hurtling over his head. He imagined
  <lb/>them to have rows of vindictively-grinning teeth turned
  <lb/>toward <add place="above" rend="caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_50_z004">him</add> as they passed.
  <lb/>He experienced a thrill of amazement as he
  <lb/>passed the battery in the field back of the grove. The
  <lb/>artillerymen were going swiftly about their tasks. They
  <lb/>were continually bending in coaxing postures over the guns.
  <lb/>They seemed to be patting them on the back and en-
  <lb/>couraging them with words. The guns stolid and un-
  <lb/>daunted, spoke with dogged valor.
  <lb/>The precise gunners were cool save for their
  <lb/>eyes which were lifted every chance toward <restore change="dstX" hand="#SC" facs="#rboc-d_50_z009">a</restore>
  <lb/>smoked-wreathed hillock from whence a hostile bat-
  <lb/>tery addressed them. Fleming pitied them as he ran.
  <lb/>Methodical idiots! Machine-like fools! Staying to
  <lb/>be eaten up! The face of a youthful rider who was
  <lb/>jerking his frantic horse with the abandon of tem-
  <lb/>per he might display in a placid barn-yard was
  <lb/>impressed deep upon his mind. He knew he looked
  <lb/><del rend="overwrite pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_50_z010">upon</del> a man who would presently be dead.
  <lb/>He saw a brigade going to the relief of it's
  <lb/>pestered <restore change="dstX" hand="#SC" facs="#rboc-d_50_z008">fellows</restore>. He scrambled into some bushes and
  <lb/>watched it, sweeping finely, keeping formation in
  <lb/>difficult places. The blue of the line was crusted
  <lb/>with steel-color and brilliant flags projected.
  <lb/>Officers were shouting.
</ab><milestone n="6" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>