<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_45"/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_45_z005"/><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_45_z007"/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_45_z006"/><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_45_z008"/><add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_45_z010"/><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_45_z011"/><metamark place="margin-bottom" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_45_z009"/><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_45_z012"/><ab>45<lb/>45<lb/>A small procession of wounded men was going
  <lb/>drearily toward the rear. It was like a flow of
  <lb/>blood from the torn body of the regiment.
  <lb/>To the right and left were the dark lines of other
  <lb/>troops. Far in front, he could see lighter masses protrud-
  <lb/>ing in points from the one woods. They were vaguely suggestive
  <lb/>of untold thousands.
  <lb/>Once he saw a tiny battery go dashing along the line
  <lb/>of the horizon. The tiny riders were beating the tiny horses.
  <lb/>From a sloping hill came the sound of cheering and
  <lb/>clashes. Smokes welled steadily up. Batteries were speaking
  <lb/>with thunderous oratorical effort. Here and there, were flags,
  <lb/>the red in the stripes dominating. They splashed bits of
  <lb/>brilliant color upon the dark troops.
  <lb/>Fleming felt the old thrill at the sight of the emblems.
  <lb/>They were like beautiful birds strangely undaunted in a storm.
  <lb/>As he listened to the din from the hill-side hill side, and
  <lb/>to a deep pulsating thunder that came from afar to the
  <lb/>right and to the lesser clamors which came from
  <lb/>many directions, it occurred to Fleming that they were
  <lb/>fighting too, over there and over there and over there.
  <lb/>Heretofore he had supposed that the battle was directly
  <lb/>under his nose.
  <lb/>As he gazed around him, Fleming felt a flash of as-
  <lb/>tonishment at the blue, pure sky and the sun-gleam-
  <lb/>ings on the trees and fields. It was surprising
  <lb/>that nature had gone tranquilly with her
  <lb/>golden processes in the midst of so much devil-
  <lb/>ment.
</ab><milestone n="6" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>