<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_53"/><ab rend="bottom"><metamark place="below" function="caret" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_53_z006">^</metamark></ab><ab> <lb/><lb/>53 <lb/>VII.<lb/>Fleming cringed as if discovered at a crime. By heav-
  <lb/>ens, they had won after all. That embecile line had remain
  <lb/>ed<add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_53_z007">and</add> become victors. He could hear the cheering.
  <lb/>He lifted himself upon his toes and looked in the
  <lb/>direction of the fight. A vast yellow cloud lay wallow-
  <lb/>ing on the tree-tops. From beneath <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_53_z001"><metamark place="inline" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_53_z001">cam</metamark></del>it came the
  <lb/>clatter of musketry. The <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_53_z002"><metamark place="inline" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_53_z002">cheers</metamark></del>hoarse cheers told of an
  <lb/>advance.
  <lb/>He turned away, sulky and angry. He felt that 
  <lb/>he had been wronged.
  <lb/>He had fled, he told himself, because annihilation 
  <lb/>was approaching. He had done his part in saving himself 
  <lb/>who was a little piece of the army. He had considered the 
  <lb/>time, he said, to be one in which it was the duty of ev-
  <lb/>ery little piece to rescue itself if possible. Later, the 
  <lb/>officers could put the little pieces together again and 
  <lb/>make a battle-front. <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_53_z003"><metamark place="inline" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_53_z003">J</metamark></del>If no little pieces were wise 
  <lb/>enough to <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_53_z004"><metamark place="inline" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_53_z004">rescue</metamark></del>save themselves from the flurry of 
  <lb/>death at such a time, why, then, were would the army 
  <lb/>be? It was all very plain that he had proceeded 
  <lb/>according to very correct and commendable rules. His 
  <lb/>actions had been sagacious things. They were full of strategy.
  <lb/>He thought of his comrades. They had staid and 
  <lb/>won. It seemed that the blind ignorance and stupid
  <lb/>ity of those little pieces had betrayed him. He had 
  <lb/>been over-turned and crushed by their lack of sense 
  <lb/>in holding a position that a little thought would 
  <lb/>have convinced them to be impossible. He, the 
  <lb/>enlightened, had fled because of his superior know-
  <lb/>ledge. He felt a great anger against his comrades.
</ab><milestone n="7" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>