<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_04"/><ab rend="top"><metamark place="margin-top" function="foliation" rend="ink" change="dStA" facs="#rboc-d_04_z014">4</metamark></ab><ab><lb/>other end. A picture from an illustrated weekly
  <lb/>was upon the log wall and three rifles were
  <lb/>paral<subst facs="#rboc-d_04_z007"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z007">l</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z007">e</add></subst><subst facs="#rboc-d_04_z015">e<del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z015">l</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z015">l</add></subst>led on pegs. Some tin dishes lay on a
  <lb/>small pile of fire-wood. Equipments were hung
  <lb/>on handy projections. The smoke from the fire
  <lb/>at times neglected the clay-chimney and wreathed
  <lb/>into the room. A small window shot an ob-
  <lb/>lique square of light upon the cluttered floor.
  <lb/>So, they were at last going to fight. On
  <lb/>the morrow, perhaps, there would be a battle and
  <lb/>he would be in it.
  <lb/>He could not convince himself of it. It
  <lb/>was too strange. He could not believe with assurance
  <lb/>that he was at last to mingle in one of those great
  <lb/>affairs of the earth.
  <lb/>He had dreamed of battles all his life--
  <lb/>of vague, bloody conflicts that had thrilled
  <lb/>him with their sweep and fire. In visions, he
  <lb/>had seen himself in many struggles. But, awake,
  <lb/>he <add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z008">had</add> regarded battles as crimson blotches on
  <lb/>the pages of the past. He had put them, as
  <lb/>things of <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z010">history</del><del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z011">,</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z009">the bygone,</add> with his thought-images of
  <lb/>heavy golden crowns and high dreary castles<subst facs="#rboc-d_04_z012"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z012">,</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_04_z012">.</add></subst>
  <lb/>There was a portion of the world's history which
  <lb/>he had regarded as the time of war, but, that,
  <lb/>he had thought, had gone over the horizon
  <lb/>and disappeared forever. 
  <lb/>From his home, his youthful eyes had looked
  <lb/>at the war in his own country with distrust.
</ab><milestone n="5" unit="leaf"/></div></body></text>