<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_42"/><ab><lb/>42.<lb/>Following this came a red rage. He developed the
  <lb/>acute exasperation of a pestered <del rend="doublestrikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_42_z001">cow</del> animal, a well-
  <lb/>meaning animal cow worried by dogs. He had a furious feeling
  <lb/>against his weapon that could only kill one man at a
  <lb/>time. He wished to rush forward and strangle with
  <lb/>his hands. He craved a power that would enable
  <lb/>him to make a mad, world-sweeping gesture and
  <lb/>brush all back. His impotency appeared to him
  <lb/>and made his rage into that of a driven beast.
  <lb/>Buried in the smoke of many rifles,<del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_42_z002"> as in a</del>
  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_42_z003">sea</del>, he his anger was not directed so much against
  <lb/>the men whom he knew were rushing toward him
  <lb/>as against the swirling battle-phantoms who were
  <lb/>choking him, <del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_42_z004">with</del> stuffing their smoke-robes down
  <lb/><subst facs="#rboc-d_42_z005"><del rend="pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_42_z005">his parched</del><add place="inline" rend="pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_42_z005"/></subst> at his throat. He fought madly for respite, for
  <lb/>air, as a babe, being smothered, attacks the
  <lb/>deadly blankets.
  <lb/>There was a blare of heated <del rend="strikethrough pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_42_z006">anger</del>, rage,
  <lb/>mingled with a certain expression of intentness,
  <lb/>on all faces. Nearly every man was making a
  <lb/>noise with his mouth. The cheers, snarls, im-
  <lb/>precations, wailings, made a wild, barbaric song.
  <lb/>The man at Fleming's elbow was babbling like an
  <lb/>infant. Jim Conklin was swearing in a loud voice.
  <lb/>From his lips came a black procession of curious
  <lb/>oaths. Suddenly, another broke out in a querelous
  <lb/>way like a man who has mislaid his hat: "Well,
  <lb/>then, why don't they support us? Why don't they
  <lb/>send supports? Do they think--"
</ab><milestone n="5" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>