<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_80"/><ab><lb/>80<lb/>Eventually, his courage expended itself upon his ob-
  <lb/>jections. The debates drained him of the fire.
  <lb/>Furthermore, various ailments had begun to cry 
  <lb/>out. In their presence, he could not persist in <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_80_z004">re-
  <lb/>maining</del> flying high with red wings of war. He 
  <lb/>tumbled head-long.
  <lb/>He discovered that he had a scorching thirst. 
  <lb/>His face was so dry and grimey that he thought he 
  <lb/>could feel his skin crackle. <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_80_z003">His feet we</del> Each bone 
  <lb/><subst facs="#rboc-d_80_z010"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_80_z010">in of</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_80_z010"/></subst> his body had an ache in it and seemingly threat-
  <lb/>ened to break. His feet were like two sores. His body, 
  <lb/>too, was calling for food. It was more powerful than 
  <lb/>a direct hunger. There was a dull, weight-like feeling 
  <lb/>in his stomach and when he moved, his head sway-
  <lb/>ed and he tottered. He could not see with distinctness. 
  <lb/>Small patches of crimson mist floated before his vision.
  <lb/>While he had been tossed by many emotions, he 
  <lb/>had not been aware of ailments. Now they beset him and 
  <lb/>made clamor. As he was at last compelled to pay 
  <lb/>attention to them, his capacity for self-hate was 
  <lb/>multiplied. He groaned from his heart and staggered 
  <lb/>off through the fields. He was not like those others, 
  <lb/><del> rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_80-0005" &gt;A desire for news kept him in the vicinity of</del> 
  <lb/><del> rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_80-0006" &gt;the battle-ground</del> he said, in despair. He now conceded 
  <lb/>it to be impossible that he should ever grow to be
  <lb/>one of them. Those pictures of glory were piteous things.
  <lb/>A desire for news kept him in the vicinity of 
  <lb/>the battle-ground. He wished to know who was winning.
  <lb/>He told himself that in all his troubles he had never 
  <lb/>lost his greed for a victory, yet, he said in a half apolog<del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_80_z008">y</del>-
  <add place="margin-left" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_80_z007"><lb/>ogetic ^</add>manner, he could not but know that a defeat this
</ab><milestone n="11" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>