<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><pb facs="#rboc-d_82"/><ab><lb/>82<lb/>
  <lb/>As these thoughts went rapidly through his mind, he sud-
  <lb/>denly turned upon them and tried to savagely thrust 
  <lb/>them away. With woe upon his face, he denounced him-
  <lb/>self as a villian. He was he said the most unutterably 
  <lb/>selfish man in existence. His mind pictured the men who 
  <lb/>would place their defiant bodies before the spear of the 
  <lb/>yelling battle-fiend and as he saw their wetltering corpses 
  <lb/>on an imagined field, he said that he was their murderer.
  <lb/>Again, <subst facs="#rboc-d_82_z013"><del rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z013">H</del><add place="inline" rend="ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z013"/></subst>he thought that he wished he was dead. He believed 
  <lb/>that he envied the corpses. Too, he achieved a species 
  <lb/>of contempt for some of them as if they <del rend="multistrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z003">had done a</del>
  <lb/><del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z001">an</del> <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z002">a wrong action</del>were guilty for thus becoming lifeless<add place="inline" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z014">.</add> 
  <lb/>They might have been killed by lucky chances, he 
  <lb/>said, before they had had opportunities to flee or 
  <lb/>before they had been really tested. Yet they would 
  <lb/>recieve laurels from traditions. He cried out bitterly 
  <lb/>that their crowns were stolen and their robes of 
  <lb/>glorious memories were shams. <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z004">Yet</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z005">However</add>, he thought it 
  <lb/>was a pity that he was not as they.
  <lb/>A defeat of the army had suggested itself to him 
  <lb/>as a means of escape from the consequences of his 
  <lb/>fall. He considered howerer that it was <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z009">very</del>use-
  <lb/>less to think of such a possibility. His education 
  <lb/>had been that success for that mighty, blue <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z010">and</del>
  <lb/><del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_82_z011">steel</del>machine was certain; that it would make 
  <lb/>victories as a contrivance turns out buttons. He pres-
  <lb/>ently discarded all his speculations in the other dir-
  <lb/>ection. He returned to the true creed of soldiers.
  <lb/>As he percieved again that it was not possible for 
  <lb/>the army to be defeated, he began to bethink him of a 
  <lb/>fine tale which he could take back to his regiment
</ab><milestone n="12" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>