<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><div><ab><pb facs="#rboc-d_78"/><lb/>78<lb/>enemy. They felt the pride of their onward movement when 
  <lb/>the whole army seemed trying to dribble down this road. 
  <lb/>They tumbled teams about with a fine feeling that it was 
  <lb/>no matter so long as their column got to the front in time. 
  <lb/>This importance made their <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z001">column</del><add place="inline" rend="no-caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z014">faces</add> stern and quiet, 
  <lb/>and the backs of the officers were very rigid.
  <lb/>As he looked at them, Fleming knew all of his
  <lb/>woe. He felt that he was regarding a procession of 
  <lb/>chosen beings. The separation was as great to him as 
  <lb/>if they had marched with weapons of flame and 
  <lb/>banners of sunlight. He could never be like them. 
  <lb/>He could have wept in his longings.
  <lb/>He searched about in his mind then for a 
  <lb/>proper malediction for the indefinite cause, that 
  <lb/>thing <del rend="doublestrikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z017">to</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z016">upon</add> which men turn the words of final blame. 
  <lb/>It was responsible for him. There lay the fault.
  <lb/>The haste of the column to reach the battle-ground 
  <lb/>struck forlorn Fleming as being something <del rend="strikethrough ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z008">more</del><add place="above" rend="no-caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z007">much finer</add> than stout 
  <lb/><del rend="overwrite pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z018">st</del>fighting. Heroes he thought, could find excuses in that 
  <lb/>long, seething l<del rend="overwrite pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z020">i</del>ane. They could retire with perfect 
  <lb/>self-respect and make explanations to the stars.
  <lb/>He wondered what those men <add place="above" rend="caret pencil" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z012">^had eaten</add> that <del rend="overwrite ink" hand="#SC" change="dstX" facs="#rboc-d_78_z013">cothey</del> could be so 
  <lb/>bitter to force their ways to chances of death. As he watched 
  <lb/>his envy grew until he wished to change lives with one of them. 
  <lb/>He would have like to have used a tremendous force, 
  <lb/>thrown off himself and became a better. Swift picture 
  <lb/>of himself apart yet in himself came to him--a blue 
  <lb/>desperate figure leading lurid charges with one knee 
  <lb/>forward and a broken blade high -- a blue 
  <lb/>determined figure standing before a crimson and steel 
  <lb/>assault getting calmly killed on a high place before
</ab><milestone n="11" unit="chapter"/></div></body></text>